https://youtu.be/29AiU8lIij8 It’s quite apparent. Yes, it sounds like that, sort of, but it’s like visual illusions.
Điều đó khá rõ ràng nhưng đại khái giống như ảo ảnh thị giác.
You’re also aware at the same time that it isn’t really like that.
Đồng thời bạn cũng nhận thấy nó cũng không hẳn như thế.
People have reported seeing a face on Mars, or Elvis in the form of a tree, or even seeing
Người ta báo rằng mình thấy một gương mặt trên sao Hỏa, hay nhìn cái cây thấy hình Elvis hay thậm chí là thấy
the Virgin Mary in a toasted cheese sandwich. This sort of expectancy effect is really common
hình ảnh Đức Mẹ đồng trinh trên một chiếc sanwich phô mai nướng. Loại hiệu ứng kỳ vọng này
throughout cognition, and psychology, more generally.
thường rất phổ biến trong nhận thức và tâm lí học.
There are certainly a lot of famous politicians who have had distorted memories. Memory evidence
Hẳn rằng có nhiều chính trị gia nổi tiếng có ký ức đau buồn. Bằng chứng ký ức ấy rất giá trị.
is precious. It needs to be preserved. It needs to be protected.
Nó cần được giữ gìn và bảo vệ.
Imagine that you’re sitting in front of an auditorium and you’re asked to perform
Hãy tưởng tượng bạn đang ngồi trước một thính phòng và được yêu cầu trình diễn
for a roomful of people by tapping out a tune for everyone to hear. How many of the 100
trước căn phòng đông nghịt người bằng cách vỗ nhịp. Bao nhiêu trong số 100 người nghe
listeners would be able to name the tune that you’re tapping?
có thể đoán được tên điệu nhạc bạn đang vỗ?